This website is not compatible with your web browser. You should [install a newer browser](https://www.google.com/chrome/). If you live in Jersey and need help upgrading call the States of Jersey web team on 440099.

Information and public services for the Island of Jersey

L'înformâtion et les sèrvices publyis pouor I'Île dé Jèrri

Search gov.je

 Search

Search gov.je  Search

gov.je privacy policy
=====================

Body Content

Introduction
------------

The Department is registered as a ‘Controller’ under the Data Protection (Jersey) Law 2018 as we collect and process personal information about you. We process and hold your information in order to provide public services and meet our statutory obligations. This notice explains how we use and share your information. Information may be collected on a paper or online form, by telephone, email, or by a member of our staff, or in some cases, by another States department.  

We will continually review and update this privacy notice to reflect changes in our services and feedback from service users, as well as to comply with changes in the law.

What information we collect about you
-------------------------------------

We collect the following types of information about you:

* name
* IP address
* user name
* email address
* address (optional)
* telephone number (optional)
* date of birth (optional)
* notification preferences (optional)

Why we collect information about you
------------------------------------

We need to collect and hold information about you, in order to:

* answer your query
* provide you with information you need
* verify you are who you say you are
* send you notifications if you subscribe to them
* investigate your complaint
* carry out the service you have requested
* to customise our site to meet your needs using cookies
* marketing data for targeted Facebook adverts

How will we use the information about you and who will we share your data with
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Protecting your privacy and looking after your personal information is important to us. We work hard to make sure that we have the right policies, training and processes in place to protect our manual and electronic information systems from loss, corruption or misuse. Where necessary we use encryption, particularly if we are transferring information out of the department. Encryption means the information is made unreadable until it reaches its destination.

We will use the information you provide in a manner that conforms to the Data Protection (Jersey) Law 2018.

We may not be able to provide you with a service unless we have enough information or your permission to use that information.

We will endeavour to keep your information accurate and up to date and not keep it for longer than is necessary. In some instances the law sets the length of time information has to be kept. Please ask to see our retention schedules for more detail about how long we retain your information.

Where necessary, we may disclose your information to other Government of Jersey departments, associated organisations (such as Parishes) and arm’s length organisations to either to fulfil your request for a service to comply with a legal obligation, or where permitted under other legislation. Examples of this include, but are not limited to: where the disclosure is necessary for the purposes of the prevention and/or detection of crime; for the purposes of meeting statutory obligations; or to prevent risk of harm to an individual, etc. These departments and organisations are obliged to keep your details securely, and only use your information for the purposes of processing your service request. We will only do this, where possible, after we have ensured that sufficient steps have been taken by the recipient to protect your personal data and where necessary we will ensure that the recipient has signed a Data Sharing Agreement. A Data Sharing Agreement sets out the purpose of the sharing and the rules that must be followed when processing your data.

We may need to pass your information to other departments or organisations outside the Government of Jersey who either process information on our behalf, or because of a legal requirement, and we will only do so, where possible, after we have ensured that sufficient steps have been taken by the recipient to protect your personal data. Other organisations we work with:

* C5 Alliance
    
* Fusion Development
    
* Switch Digital
    
* Granicus  
    
* Govmetric
    
* Talentlink (job applications)

We will not disclose any information that you provide ‘in confidence’, to anyone else without your permission, except in the few situations where disclosure is required by law, or where we have good reason to believe that failing to share the information would put someone else at risk. You will be told about this unless there are exceptional reasons not to do so. 

We do not share or process your information overseas. We do not use web services that are hosted outside the European Economic Area.

### When you sign up for our services

We store your contact information to understand your needs and provide you with a personalised service.

### When you contact us

If you contact us asking for information, we may need to send your enquiry to other government departments associated organisations and suppliers, to respond to your request.

### Cookies

We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small files which can be stored on your computer when you visit a website. These files contain information about the webpages you look at so that the next time you visit the site it can be customised to meet your needs.

Read our [Cookies policy](https://www.gov.je/Pages/CookiesPolicy.aspx) to find out more.

### Links to other websites

Links on our website may lead to other websites which are not under our control. Using these links does not mean these organisations can access information about you which is held by the States of Jersey.

This privacy policy only covers the States of Jersey website (www.gov.je). Websites linked to, and from, this site are not covered by this policy, so you should always read the privacy statement on that website.

The States of Jersey is not responsible for the content of external websites.

### GovMetric feedback

We use ServMetric (also known as GovMetric) for gathering customer feedback on the services an organisation or company provides with the aim of improving those services. The survey answers and information you provide help us to improve our services and will be stored.

If you leave your contact information asking for information or update, we may need to send your enquiry to other government departments to respond to your request.

### Online forms (Granicus)

We use Granicus for our online forms. The information and data you provide is unique to each form. Privacy details are included on the individual form.

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to help us understand how you engage with our website so that we can continually improve your experience.

When you visit gov.je your browser automatically sends certain information to Google. This includes, for example, the web address of the page that you're visiting and your IP address.

Learn [how to control the information your browser sends to Google on Google's website](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

### Facebook pixel

We use Facebook pixel for marketing purposes. The Facebook Pixel is used for Facebook Ads and Facebook Analytics. It does use private data and you will need to ask for prior consent. Facebook has also implemented flexible ways for their users to see and control how the pixel is used on partner websites.

The Facebook pixel receives these types of data:

* HTTP Headers: anything present in HTTP headers. HTTP Headers are a standard web protocol sent between any browser request and any server on the internet. HTTP Headers include IP addresses, information about the web browser, page location, document, referrer and person using the website
* pixel-specific data: includes Pixel ID and the Facebook Cookie
* button click data: includes any buttons clicked by site visitors, the labels of those buttons and any pages visited as a result of the button clicks
* optional values: developers and marketers can optionally choose to send additional information about the visit through conversion tracking. Example custom data events are conversion value, page type, and more
* form field names: includes website field names like 'email', 'address', 'quantity' for when you purchase a product or service. We don't capture field values unless you include them as part of Advanced Matching, conversion tracking, or user properties

You can [change your ad preferences at any time using your Facebook login](https://www.facebook.com/ads/settings "Facebook Ad Preferences").

### IP address

Your computer’s IP address is a number assigned to your computer when you use the internet. This is recorded automatically in a log file when you visit our site. This log file does not contain any personal identifiable information about you.

We will not pass your information to organisations for marketing or sales purposes or for any commercial use without your prior express consent.

Changes to this policy
----------------------

We may, at any time, revise this privacy statement without notice so you should check it regularly. Continued use of the States of Jersey website after a change has been made is your acceptance of the change.

Contact
=======

Web Services

* E   [digital@gov.je](mailto:digital@gov.je)

Digital Services  
Union Street  
St Helier  
Jersey  
JE2 3DN

In this section
===============

* [How to contact us and communicate with us using British Sign Language (BSL)](https://www.gov.je/Pages/SignVideo.aspx)

Related links
=============

Our sites

Find us on social media

* © States of Jersey 2010 - 2024
